<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>macaroni on Macaroni OS</title>
    <link>https://www.macaronios.org/tags/macaroni/</link>
    <description>Recent content in macaroni on Macaroni OS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.macaronios.org/tags/macaroni/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Macaroni OS Phoenix 23.03.01 is out!</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.03.01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.03.01/</guid>
      <description>While we have worked on preparing the new ISOs for the release 23.03 we have figured out that was better to bump a new release with the changes of the Calamares plugin to migrate our ISOs to kernel 6.1. In particular, the ISOs for Desktops have now the kernel 6.1.18 with built-in integration with new Realtek wifi cards. Unluckily not yet the cards 8852b e 8852be that will be available on branch 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macaroni OS Phoenix 23.03 is out!</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.03/</guid>
      <description>Finally, after two months of hard work, the release Phoenix 23.03 is out and is the first Desktop release under the new macaronios.org domain.
In these two months, we had to follow infrastructure issues (broken hard disks) and create the new Macaroni network. This is one of the reasons we have skipped the release of February.
We want to thank again the GARR consortium that is now our primary mirror under our CDN and this will permit in the next weeks to expose again the ISOs download page and our LXD images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>macaronios.org is here!</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/new-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/new-domain/</guid>
      <description>After 1 year of incubation under the Funtoo Foundation, the Macaroni OS has now its domain macaronios.org and its infrastructure. Really, thanks to the Funtoo Foundation and Daniel Robbins for its support that helped to Macaroni OS to be here today.
From the infrastructure aspect nothing is changed, all compilation tasks are executed over MottainaiCI cluster but with less resource power for now.
We hope that the community will help us to maintain the infrastructure costs with donations over our Github Sponsor or with VMs donations for compilation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
