<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>release on Macaroni OS</title>
    <link>https://www.macaronios.org/tags/release/</link>
    <description>Recent content in release on Macaroni OS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.macaronios.org/tags/release/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Macaroni-Security Repository is here!</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.08/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.08/</guid>
      <description>Finally, it&amp;rsquo;s available the new macaroni-security repository!
Considering that the Funtoo release 1.4-prime is in EOL, we will use the macaroni-security repository to share security patches and updates of Browsers, Devs tools, and other packages meantime we rebooting Phoenix&amp;rsquo;s branch to Funtoo Next.
Due to this change, all users using Macaroni Phoenix MUST add the macaroni-security repository before executing any update.
$&amp;gt; luet repo update $&amp;gt; luet i repository/macaroni-security $&amp;gt; luet repo update $&amp;gt; luet upgrade The repository macaroni-security uses the new tree v2 which requires luet version 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New features incoming with 23.06 releases!</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.06.01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.06.01/</guid>
      <description>We have important news to share: the development of our PMS continues and finally, we have rewritten the method used to bump a new revision of the repository.
This enhancement integrates a new way to create the tree tarball used on repo update command. This new implementation breaks the existing implementation. For this reason, we will migrate to the new implementation in August or September. This will permit to users to upgrade to the minimal luet version requires: version 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macaroni OS Phoenix 23.05 is out!</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.05/</guid>
      <description>We are happy to announce the new release Phoenix 23.05 that contains the first significant change needed to migrate the Phoenix tree from the Funtoo release 1.4-prime to the Next release, an activity that will be completed for the subsequent releases. In particular, with this release is dropped the support of Python 2.7 in EOL for a lot of months. The package dev-lang-2.7/python is yet available because a lot of Funtoo packages depend on it for compilation but it&amp;rsquo;s discouraged the use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macaroni OS Phoenix 23.03.02 is out!</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.03.02/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.03.02/</guid>
      <description>After receiving the first notifications we caught an issue in our last ISOs related to the split of the Grub package done to divide the grub-emu binary. It&amp;rsquo;s been removed for error the Grub&amp;rsquo;s patches related to ext4 1.47.0 and of Macaroni initramfs naming.
Without the patch the default installation fails on setup grub because it&amp;rsquo;s used ext4 and an unknown filesystem error is generated by grub.
The new ISOs will be available in two days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macaroni OS Phoenix 23.03.01 is out!</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.03.01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.03.01/</guid>
      <description>While we have worked on preparing the new ISOs for the release 23.03 we have figured out that was better to bump a new release with the changes of the Calamares plugin to migrate our ISOs to kernel 6.1. In particular, the ISOs for Desktops have now the kernel 6.1.18 with built-in integration with new Realtek wifi cards. Unluckily not yet the cards 8852b e 8852be that will be available on branch 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macaroni OS Phoenix 23.03 is out!</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.03/</guid>
      <description>Finally, after two months of hard work, the release Phoenix 23.03 is out and is the first Desktop release under the new macaronios.org domain.
In these two months, we had to follow infrastructure issues (broken hard disks) and create the new Macaroni network. This is one of the reasons we have skipped the release of February.
We want to thank again the GARR consortium that is now our primary mirror under our CDN and this will permit in the next weeks to expose again the ISOs download page and our LXD images.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
