<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Macaroni OS</title>
    <link>https://www.macaronios.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Macaroni OS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.macaronios.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Phoenix 23.11 based on Funtoo Next!</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.11/</guid>
      <description>We are happy to announce that after three intense months we have finally completed the migration of Macaroni Phoenix to a Funtoo Next based system.
This is a really good milestone for us because after two years we have been a big step ahead, before becoming an independent project, entering in the Docker Sponsored program, and now with the first big release upgrade. The world is buggy so we are sure that something will be also present in this first big step but we hope the community and the users will be happy about how things grow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Macaroni-Security Repository is here!</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.08/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.08/</guid>
      <description>Finally, it&amp;rsquo;s available the new macaroni-security repository!
Considering that the Funtoo release 1.4-prime is in EOL, we will use the macaroni-security repository to share security patches and updates of Browsers, Devs tools, and other packages meantime we rebooting Phoenix&amp;rsquo;s branch to Funtoo Next.
Due to this change, all users using Macaroni Phoenix MUST add the macaroni-security repository before executing any update.
$&amp;gt; luet repo update $&amp;gt; luet i repository/macaroni-security $&amp;gt; luet repo update $&amp;gt; luet upgrade The repository macaroni-security uses the new tree v2 which requires luet version 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New features incoming with 23.06 releases!</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.06.01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.06.01/</guid>
      <description>We have important news to share: the development of our PMS continues and finally, we have rewritten the method used to bump a new revision of the repository.
This enhancement integrates a new way to create the tree tarball used on repo update command. This new implementation breaks the existing implementation. For this reason, we will migrate to the new implementation in August or September. This will permit to users to upgrade to the minimal luet version requires: version 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macaroni OS Phoenix 23.05 is out!</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.05/</guid>
      <description>We are happy to announce the new release Phoenix 23.05 that contains the first significant change needed to migrate the Phoenix tree from the Funtoo release 1.4-prime to the Next release, an activity that will be completed for the subsequent releases. In particular, with this release is dropped the support of Python 2.7 in EOL for a lot of months. The package dev-lang-2.7/python is yet available because a lot of Funtoo packages depend on it for compilation but it&amp;rsquo;s discouraged the use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macaroni OS Phoenix 23.03.02 is out!</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.03.02/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.03.02/</guid>
      <description>After receiving the first notifications we caught an issue in our last ISOs related to the split of the Grub package done to divide the grub-emu binary. It&amp;rsquo;s been removed for error the Grub&amp;rsquo;s patches related to ext4 1.47.0 and of Macaroni initramfs naming.
Without the patch the default installation fails on setup grub because it&amp;rsquo;s used ext4 and an unknown filesystem error is generated by grub.
The new ISOs will be available in two days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macaroni OS Phoenix 23.03.01 is out!</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.03.01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.03.01/</guid>
      <description>While we have worked on preparing the new ISOs for the release 23.03 we have figured out that was better to bump a new release with the changes of the Calamares plugin to migrate our ISOs to kernel 6.1. In particular, the ISOs for Desktops have now the kernel 6.1.18 with built-in integration with new Realtek wifi cards. Unluckily not yet the cards 8852b e 8852be that will be available on branch 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macaroni OS Phoenix 23.03 is out!</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.03/</guid>
      <description>Finally, after two months of hard work, the release Phoenix 23.03 is out and is the first Desktop release under the new macaronios.org domain.
In these two months, we had to follow infrastructure issues (broken hard disks) and create the new Macaroni network. This is one of the reasons we have skipped the release of February.
We want to thank again the GARR consortium that is now our primary mirror under our CDN and this will permit in the next weeks to expose again the ISOs download page and our LXD images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>macaronios.org is here!</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/new-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/new-domain/</guid>
      <description>After 1 year of incubation under the Funtoo Foundation, the Macaroni OS has now its domain macaronios.org and its infrastructure. Really, thanks to the Funtoo Foundation and Daniel Robbins for its support that helped to Macaroni OS to be here today.
From the infrastructure aspect nothing is changed, all compilation tasks are executed over MottainaiCI cluster but with less resource power for now.
We hope that the community will help us to maintain the infrastructure costs with donations over our Github Sponsor or with VMs donations for compilation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Inc.</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/partners/docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 11:06:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/partners/docker/</guid>
      <description>The Docker Inc. approved the Macaroni OS to the Docker-Sponsored Open Source program that permits to remove the rate-limit for all users pulling public images from our namespace.
The Macaroni OS Docker images are available on our macaronios organization.
Thank you very much for your support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consortium GARR</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/partners/garr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 11:06:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/partners/garr/</guid>
      <description>GARR is the ultra-broadband network dedicated to the Italian research and education community. Its main objective is to provide high-performance connectivity and to develop innovative services for the daily activities of researchers, professors and students as well as for international collaboration.
GARR network is designed and managed by Consortium GARR, a non-profit association founded under the auspices of the Ministry of Education, University and Research. The members are CNR, ENEA, INAF, INFN, INGV and CRUI Foundation, representing all Italian universities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consortium TOP-IX</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/partners/topix/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 11:06:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/partners/topix/</guid>
      <description>The TOP-IX Consortium has been actively working on several fronts: managing the Internet Exchange infrastructure (the reason for its initial foundation in 2002); running the Development Program, we are been added to this program; the Streaming platform, which has been providing support for technological innovation projects since 2006; and the Streaming platform, which enabled the Consortium to act as the official provider of the Berlinale Film Festival since 2006.
The Consortium TOP-IX supplies a Development node that helps us with the building process of the Macaroni packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contacts</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/contact/main/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/contact/main/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Funtoo zone</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/docs/funtoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/docs/funtoo/</guid>
      <description>Main differences between Funtoo and Macaroni OS # 1. Static UID/GID # The system UID (user ID) and GID (group ID) of the major services are statically allocated and managed through the entities tool and his catalog. This helps to have an more linear installation between systems and help on share network filesystem like NFS.
It possible to see the list of the available uid/gid with the following command:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/docs/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/docs/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Getting Started # Install Macaroni ISO # Choice the right ISO for your requirements from our Download page.
1.Validate downloaded ISO # After the you have downloaded the ISOs file, I suggest to verify the quality of the download throw our SHA256 hash:
$ sha256sum Macaroni-Funtoo-Phoenix-Gnome-23.03.02.iso 8637d8c6ba72f8694aabd631f038473acaadd0fbb8fc9fa7cec7bb0d495f1f54 Macaroni-Funtoo-Phoenix-Gnome-23.03.02.iso $ cat Macaroni-Funtoo-Phoenix-Gnome-23.03.02.iso.sha256 8637d8c6ba72f8694aabd631f038473acaadd0fbb8fc9fa7cec7bb0d495f1f54 If the download is correct the hash will be the same.
Until the issue #7 will be fixed you need to compare the sha256 manually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networking</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/docs/networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/docs/networking/</guid>
      <description>Networking # Macaroni OS inherits all network configuration ways from Funtoo. In particular, every release could contain one or more ways and/or technologies.
Hereinafter, a table with the different technologies and the availability in the Macaroni releases.
Technology Release Phoenix Release Terragon Release Eagle Network Manager Yes Yes Yes Core Network Yes Yes No SystemD Networkd No No Yes In our ISOs, we use Network Manager that is which seems better integrated with Calamares Installer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Package Manager System</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/docs/pms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/docs/pms/</guid>
      <description>Package Manager System # The Package Manager System of the Macaroni OS is luet. It&amp;rsquo;s written in Golang and it has zero dependencies and permits to prepare environments &amp;ldquo;from scratch&amp;rdquo;.
It was initially based on branch 0.16 of the Mocaccino OS&amp;rsquo;s PMS but later is totally rewritten.
It&amp;rsquo;s composed of two different binary: the luet binary is the PMS client used by users to install packages and the luet-build binary is used to build packages and bump a new repository revision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Story</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/docs/story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/docs/story/</guid>
      <description>I write this article because I think that it&amp;rsquo;s needed to understand the story to improve things and instead follow the original choices when they make sense.
The Origins # After a lot of years working with opensource packages, I can for sure to said that there are so many possibilities to configure our systems that it isn&amp;rsquo;t sufficient one life to test all combinations.
But the power to choose is one of the more powerful things that the open-source world gift and the same packages often are created with the possibility to compile and build them in different ways.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
