<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>eagle on Macaroni OS</title>
    <link>https://www.macaronios.org/tags/eagle/</link>
    <description>Recent content in eagle on Macaroni OS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.macaronios.org/tags/eagle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Phoenix 25.06 Released!</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-25.06/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-25.06/</guid>
      <description>The Phoenix is reborn! We are excited to share the new release of Phoenix 25.06 now based on MARK stack, in particular based on mark-iii branch.
A long time is passed from the previous release, but because the team is been busy with the big work done in the last year of the M.A.R.K. stack that have a lot to improve but set the base of new features and characteristics that will permit to the Macaroni OS to improve in the next years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phoenix 24.08.01 Released!</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-24.08.01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-24.08.01/</guid>
      <description>Phoenix release have a new look! We are happy to announce the Macaroni Phoenix 24.08.01 release, a minor release with some cool new changes.
This new release come with a new Plymouth Theme with Macaroni OS logo that will be installed by default in all new installation.
In this release the GTK default Theme is Orchis that together with the new Papirus icons gift a very new look and feel to the our DE based on GTK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M.A.R.K. is born!</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-24.08/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-24.08/</guid>
      <description>Funtoo is dead, long live to M.A.R.K.! Is just in the previous post that I wrote about how many communities are in difficult and that is need new lymph from young developers and at the begin of July with a pain in the heart that I received the news shared from Daniel Robbins about the Funtoo shutdown.
These the words shared by him: &amp;ldquo;All Good Things Must Come to an End&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Releases 24.04 ready!</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-24.04/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-24.04/</guid>
      <description>We are excited to announce the releases of Phoenix 24.04, Terragon 24.04 and Eagle 24.04! Thank you to all people help on this!
This release proves that we aren&amp;rsquo;t only a distribution that uses Funtoo but also tries to explore new areas for both the Funtoo Community and our users. We want to help the Opensource world to increase its popularity and its features or at least try. This is a hard mission, that requires time, but we believe in this and we will always combat this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phoenix 23.12.01, Eagle 23.12.01 and Terragon 23.12!</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.12.01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.12.01/</guid>
      <description>Happy new year to all Macaroni OS and Funtoo users!
We are happy to announce a new bugfix release for Phoenix and Eagle 23.12.01 based on the tree of 23.12 and the release Terragon 23.12:
We have autogen the Apache package, a fix that will be available for Funtoo users in harvester/24.01 soon. This permits an upgrade to version 2.4.58 with tons of security fixes. See later for the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phoenix 23.12 and Eagle 23.12!</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/blog/phoenix-23.12/</guid>
      <description>Macaroni OS is about two years old and we want to thank all the people who helped to reach this result.
Thank you!
For this reason, without to have a complete build pipeline for a new version of the Phoenix release, we want to tag the release 23.12 of Macaroni Phoenix with anothers big steps:
This releaes contains the upgrade of ZFS to version 2.2.2 with important bugfix of the release 2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
