<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Partners on Macaroni OS</title>
    <link>https://www.macaronios.org/partners/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Partners on Macaroni OS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 11:06:54 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.macaronios.org/partners/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Consortium TOP-IX</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/partners/topix/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 11:06:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/partners/topix/</guid>
      <description>The TOP-IX Consortium has been actively working on several fronts: managing the Internet Exchange infrastructure (the reason for its initial foundation in 2002); running the Development Program, we have been added to this program; the Streaming platform, which has been providing support for technological innovation projects since 2006; and the Streaming platform, which enabled the Consortium to act as the official provider of the Berlinale Film Festival since 2006.
The Consortium TOP-IX supplies a Development node that helps us with the building process of the Macaroni packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Inc.</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/partners/docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 11:06:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/partners/docker/</guid>
      <description>The Docker Inc. approved the Macaroni OS to the Docker-Sponsored Open Source program that permits to remove the rate-limit for all users pulling public images from our namespace.
The Macaroni OS Docker images are available on our macaronios organization.
Thank you very much for your support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consortium GARR</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/partners/garr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 11:06:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/partners/garr/</guid>
      <description>GARR is the ultra-broadband network dedicated to the Italian research and education community. Its main objective is to provide high-performance connectivity and to develop innovative services for the daily activities of researchers, professors and students as well as for international collaboration.
GARR network is designed and managed by Consortium GARR, a non-profit association founded under the auspices of the Ministry of Education, University and Research. The members are CNR, ENEA, INAF, INFN, INGV and CRUI Foundation, representing all Italian universities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
