<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Macaroni OS</title>
    <link>https://www.macaronios.org/docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Macaroni OS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.macaronios.org/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Funtoo zone</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/docs/funtoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/docs/funtoo/</guid>
      <description>Main differences between Funtoo and Macaroni OS # 1. Static UID/GID # The system UID (user ID) and GID (group ID) of the major services are statically allocated and managed through the entities tool and his catalog. This helps to have a more linear installation between systems and help on share network filesystems like NFS.
It is possible to see the list of the available uid/gid with the following commands:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/docs/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/docs/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Getting Started # Install Macaroni ISO # Choose the right ISO for your requirements from our Download page.
1.Validate downloaded ISO # After the you have downloaded the ISOs file, I suggest to verify the quality of the download with our SHA256 hash:
$ sha256sum Macaroni-Funtoo-Phoenix-Gnome-23.03.02.iso 8637d8c6ba72f8694aabd631f038473acaadd0fbb8fc9fa7cec7bb0d495f1f54 Macaroni-Funtoo-Phoenix-Gnome-23.03.02.iso $ cat Macaroni-Funtoo-Phoenix-Gnome-23.03.02.iso.sha256 8637d8c6ba72f8694aabd631f038473acaadd0fbb8fc9fa7cec7bb0d495f1f54 If the download is correct the hash will be the same.
2.Flash your USB drive # To write an ISO there are different tools and ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networking</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/docs/networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/docs/networking/</guid>
      <description>Networking # Macaroni OS inherits all network configuration ways from Funtoo. In particular, every release could contain one or more ways and/or technologies.
Hereinafter, a table with the different technologies and the availability in the Macaroni releases.
Technology Release Phoenix Release Terragon Release Eagle Network Manager Yes Yes Yes Core Network Yes Yes No SystemD Networkd No No Yes In our ISOs, we use Network Manager that is which seems better integrated with Calamares Installer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Package Manager System</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/docs/pms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/docs/pms/</guid>
      <description>Package Manager System # The Package Manager System of the Macaroni OS is luet. It&amp;rsquo;s written in Golang and it has zero dependencies and permits to prepare environments &amp;ldquo;from scratch&amp;rdquo;.
It was initially based on branch 0.16 of the Mocaccino OS&amp;rsquo;s PMS but later is totally rewritten.
It&amp;rsquo;s composed of two different binary: the luet binary is the PMS client used by users to install packages and the luet-build binary is used to build packages and bump a new repository revision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sambuca Anise Stack</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/docs/sambuca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/docs/sambuca/</guid>
      <description>Sambuca Anise Stack # The Sambuca Anise Stack is the stack related to the Macaroni binary mainly managed by the package manager anise that could be used by the users to install, remove and/or update installed packages.
Macaroni OS Phoenix # The Phoenix release is the first release created and the only release at the moment for the Desktop. The codename phoenix is related to the immortal bird associated with Greek mythology that cyclically regenerates or is otherwise born again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Story</title>
      <link>https://www.macaronios.org/docs/story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.macaronios.org/docs/story/</guid>
      <description>I write this article because I think that it&amp;rsquo;s needed to understand the story to improve things and instead follow the original choices when they make sense.
The Origins # After a lot of years working with opensource packages, I can for sure to said that there are so many possibilities to configure our systems that it isn&amp;rsquo;t sufficient one life to test all combinations.
But the power to choose is one of the more powerful things that the open-source world gift and the same packages often are created with the possibility to compile and build them in different ways.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
